neomobile.net 2017-12-30

# Neomobile Privacy and Cookie policy

#### In this page, we describe the manner in which we manage this website, with specific regard to the processing of visitors’ personal data.

This Privacy Policy constitutes a notice on personal data processing, provided pursuant to article 13 of Italian legislative decree no. 196/2003 – “Code on the Protection of Personal Data” – (the “ **Code** ”), to all visitors which come across the website of Neomobile S.p.A., a company with registered offices in Via della Sierra Nevada, 60, 00144 Rome (the “ **Data Controller** ” or the “ **Company** ”).

Thus, this notice is provided to visitors exclusively with regard to the Company’s website, and does not cover other websites which the visitor may access via links __ included in the website, nor does it cover other services provided by the Data Controller through other means/websites. Please refer to the specific privacy policies of such services, in order to know how the Company processes personal data of users which subscribe to its services.

### **Personal Data processed**

Considering that, pursuant to article 4(1)(B) of the Code, Personal Data means “ _any information regarding a natural person, identified or identifiable, also indirectly, by reference to ant other information, including a personal identification number_ ”, we inform you that the electronic systems and the software procedures in place which allow this website to function, acquire some personal data while running, the transmission of which is implied in the use of internet communication protocols.

This is, thus, information which is not collected in order to be associated to identified data subjects, but rather data which, by its very nature might, if elaborated and associated with data held by third parties, allow the identification of the users. This category of data includes IP addresses or domain names of the computer used by the visitors to access the website, the requests made by such visitors, the timing of the requests, etc.

This data is used with the sole scope of obtaining statistical and anonymous information regarding the use of the Company’s website, and to ensure that it functions correctly; it is, thus, erased immediately after being used. Such data might also be used for the identification of liabilities in case of possible electronic crimes against this website.

### **Personal Data spontanously submitted by the visitors**

The spontaneous, explicit and voluntary sending of e-mails to the e-mail addresses indicated in the Company’s website determines that the Company acquires the sender’s e-mail address (which is needed in order to allow the Company to reply) and all other personal data which the sender might have included in the message sent to the Data Controller.

In case of voluntary submission of a _curriculum vitae_ through the “Join Us!” section of  the website, the candidate will receive a specific privacy notice by reference to the processing of their personal data, at their first contact with the Company after the _curriculum vitae_ has been submitted.

### **Cookie Policy**

This policy explains how cookies are used on Neomobile’s website, and, below, how you can control the cookies that may be used on this site.

**What are cookies?**

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. A cookie can be thought of as an internet user’s identification card, which tell a web site when the user has returned. They were designed to be a reliable mechanism for websites to remember stateful information (such as items in a shopping cart) or to record the user’s browsing activity (clicking particular buttons, logging in etc.). Cookies can be “persistent” or “session” cookies. Persistent cookies remain on your computer when you have gone offline, while session cookies are deleted as soon as you close your web browser.

**What is session cookie?**

A session cookie, also known as an in-memory cookie or transient cookie, exists only in temporary memory while the user navigates the website. Web browsers normally delete session cookies when the user closes the browser. Unlike other cookies, session cookies do not have an expiration date assigned to them, which is how the browser knows to treat them as session cookies.

**What is persistent cookie?**

Instead of expiring when the web browser is closed as session cookies do, persistent cookies expire at a specific date or after a specific length of time. This means that, for the cookie’s entire lifespan (which can be as long or as short as its creators want), its information will be transmitted to the server every time the user visits the website that it belongs to, or every time the user views a resource belonging to that website from another website (such as an advertisement).

**How to change cookie settings on your browser**

Most internet browsers accept cookies automatically, but you can change the settings of your browser prevent automatic acceptance or erase them.

You can find here more information:

**Internet Explorer**  <http://support.microsoft.com/kb/278835>

**Chrome:**  [http://support.google.com/chrome/bin/answer.py?hl=en-GB&answer=95647](http://support.google.com/chrome/bin/answer.py?hl=en-GB&answer=95647)

**Safari:**  <https://support.apple.com/kb/PH17191?locale=en_US>

**Firefox:**  [http://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/ Enabling%20and%20disabling%20cookies](http://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/Enabling%20and%20disabling%20cookies)

**Android:**  [http://support.google.com/mobile/bin/answer.py?hl=en&answer=169022](http://support.google.com/mobile/bin/answer.py?hl=en&answer=169022)

**Opera:**  <http://www.opera.com/browser/tutorials/security/privacy/>

**Types of cookie that may be used during your visit to this Neomobile website**

We don’t list every single cookie used by name – but for each type of cookie you can find information on how to control it.

**Third-party service cookies**

**Analytics cookies**

These monitor how visitors move around the Website and how they reached it. This is used so that we can see general figures on type of content users prefer, for instance, or number of pages visited per session.

**Google Analytics  **[Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) **  – **[Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout)

Social sharing, video and other services we offer are run by other companies. These companies may drop cookies on your computer when you use them on our site or if you are already logged in to them.

Please find below the links providing specific data for each third-party:

  * Facebook’s data use policy: <http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/your-info-on-other>
  * LinkedIn cookie policy <https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie_policy>
  * Instagram about cookies <https://instagram.com/legal/cookies/>
  * Twitter’s privacy policy <https://twitter.com/privacy>
  * Tweet quote <http://www.unboxinteractive.com/privacy/>
  * YouTube video player cookie policy <http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/faq/#toc-cookies>
  * Jetpack <http://www.jetpack.com/privacy>
  * JobVite <http://www.jobvite.com/privacy-policy/>

From the moment of the installation of cookies and other tracking systems operated by third parties through the services used within this site, they cannot be technically controlled by the Publisher. For complete information, the user must consult the privacy policy of any third party service listed in this document.

### **Modalities of data processing**

Personal Data is processed through electronic means and for the period which is strictly necessary in order to fulfill the scope for which such data was collected.

In such regard, specific security measures are in place which aim at preventing the loss of data, possible illegal or otherwise misuse of the data, as well as unauthorized access to the data.

### **Rights of the data subjects**

We inform you that the persons to which the personal data refer are given specific rights under article 7 of the Code. In accordance with such article, data subjects are entitled to:

  * obtain confirmation of the existence (or non-existence) of personal data which regard them, as well as their communication in an intelligible manner;
  * obtain the updating, correction or, when of interest, the integration of the data, the cancellation, the anonymisation or the blocking of data processed against the law, including data which retention is no longer necessary for the fulfillment of the scope for which it was collected or subsequently processed;
  * oppose, in whole or in part, for legitimate reasons, to the processing of personal data which regard them.

Any requests may be addressed to the following e-mail: [info@neomobile.com](mailto:info@neomobile.com)
